In this tutorial video, we use the Doshi Marvelous Designer 11 version.
If you need to learn Marvelous Designer 10 and other version software, please watch the previous video.
In order to make it easier to learn, the Doshi Marvelous Designer 11 version is used in this tutorial.
In Marvelous Designer, you can use multiple line tools in 3D or 2D windows to merge the version.
In this video, we will learn how to use the sewing tool in 3D window to merge the costume.
By merging the basic version in 3D window, you will learn how to merge the costume and help you understand how to sew in the 2D window.
Open the project file you saved before.
This T-shirt is very simple, we use the line sewing tool to complete all the creation of the sewing line.
For other sewing line tools,
we will explain in the next tutorial.
Put your mouse on the 3D window editor sewing line tool.
Select the line sewing tool in the drop-down menu.
The line sewing tool is used to create the sewing line between the lines.
You can only choose one line at a time.
You can't choose a line made up of multiple lines.
As long as you click two lines at a time, you can merge them together.
It's very simple.
Please note that all sewing lines have their own direction of merging.
This will affect the effect of the sewing line.
Therefore, when you click to create the sewing line,
you should pay attention to the position of the click.
As a reference, I first click a line near the top of the mouse,
and then click another line near the bottom of the mouse.
The created sewing line is crossed.
The reason for the crossing of the sewing line is that
the position of the mouse click does not match,
and the mixing direction is opposite.
First, create the sewing line in the front and back.
Pay attention to the 2D window.
After creating the sewing line,
you can see that the sewing line appears in the 2D window at the same time.
If you are doing more complicated clothing,
the 3D sewing line tool will help you
create the right sewing line faster and more clearly.
Create the front and back of the sewing line.
Pay attention to the 2D window at the side of the sewing line.
After we create the sewing line on one side,
the other side will also automatically create the sewing line,
because the front and back pieces have their own symmetrical panels.
Please observe the 2D window to understand
which of the two side sewing lines is the only one to be sewn.
Continue to complete the shoulder sewing line,
pay attention to the direction of matching.
Next is the sleeve sewing line.
We will learn how the sleeve is combined with the large panel.
Click on the sleeve on the front,
then click on the corresponding sleeve,
then open the 2D window.
After opening the 2D window,
select the angle to the back,
complete the sewing line of the back sleeve and the back sleeve.
Now I believe you already understand
why we created these panels
when we used the column symmetrical panel function,
because this way we can save the time
to create the other side of the sewing line.
Then click on the sleeve,
then click on the sleeve,
and then click on the sleeve,
and then click on the sleeve.
Next, we will create the sleeve seam line.
After creating the sewing line,
turn the angle to see if there are any missed sewing lines.
Then we will complete the pocket sewing line.
Click on the sewing line
After adding all the powder lines, press the control button to start the simulation and put the costume on the virtual model.
When the costume is more complicated and clever, the simulation will take longer.
If you want to stop the simulation, please press the control button again or click the simulation button.
Please save your project file, and we will continue to use it after the next tutorial.